JINGYAN WANG

334 Groseclose Building, 755 Ferst Drive NW, Atlanta, GA 30332

Web: https://jingyanw.github.io/ Email: jingyanw@gatech.edu Phone: 510-604-2427

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

My research interests are in *statistical machine learning* and *fairness*. Specifically, my research studies the foundations of high-stakes decision-making and evaluation processes, such as hiring, admissions and peer review. I consider three components that play critical roles in such processes — algorithms, people, and policies. I draw inspirations from psychology to model real-world phenomena, develop theoretical guarantees using tools from statistics and computer science, conduct crowdsourcing experiments, and implement policy changes that make practical impacts.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Georgia Institute of Technology

2021 – present

Ronald J. and Carol T. Beerman President's Postdoctoral Fellow H. Milton Stewart School of Industrial and Systems Engineering Host: Ashwin Pananjady

Simons Institute for the Theory of Computing

11.2021

Visiting postdoc

Program: Computational Complexity of Statistical Inference

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University

2015 - 2021

Ph.D. in Robotics

Master of Science in Robotics

Thesis: "Towards Understanding and Mitigating Biases"

Advisor: Nihar B. Shah

University of California, Berkeley

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences

Minor in Mathematics

Graduated with Highest Honors

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS (* indicates authors in alphabetical order)

- Jingyan Wang, Ashwin Pananjady
 Modeling and Correcting Bias in Sequential Evaluation arXiv preprint 2205.01607
 Under review at Operations Research, 2022.
- Gregory Kehne*, Ariel D. Procaccia*, Jingyan Wang*
 Recruitment Strategies That Take a Chance
 The Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.
- Jingyan Wang, Carmel Baharav, Nihar B. Shah, Anita Williams Woolley, R. Ravi *Allocation Schemes in Analytic Evaluation: Applicant-Centric Holistic or Attribute-Centric Segmented?* AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing (HCOMP), 2022.

- Komal Dhull, Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah, Yuanzhi Li, R. Ravi
 A Heuristic for Statistical Seriation The Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2021.
- Jingyan Wang, Ivan Stelmakh, Yuting Wei, Nihar B. Shah
 Debiasing Evaluations That Are Biased by Evaluations

 AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021.
 Accepted with minor revisions at Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR), 2022.
- Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah, R. Ravi Stretching the Effectiveness of MLE from Accuracy to Bias for Pairwise Comparisons International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2020.
- Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah
 Your 2 is My 1, Your 3 is My 9: Handling Arbitrary Miscalibrations in Ratings International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2019.

Best Student Paper Award

Appeared as "Ranking and Rating Rankings and Ratings" at AAAI 2020 Sister Conference Track.

- Jingyan Wang, Olga Russakovsky, Deva Ramanan
 The More You Look, the More You See: towards General Object Understanding through Recursive Refinement
 Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2018.
- KV Rashmi, Preetum Nakkiran, Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah, Kannan Ramchandran Having Your Cake and Eating It Too: Jointly Optimal Codes for I/O, Storage and Network-bandwidth in Distributed Storage Systems.

Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2015.

Picked as the Best Paper by StorageMojo

Lei Tian, Jingyan Wang, Laura Waller
 3D differential phase-contrast microscopy with computational illumination using an LED array
 Optics Letters 39, 1326-1329, 2014.

TALKS

• Understanding and Improving Evaluation: People, Algorithms, and Design	
Peking University	2023
Carnegie Mellon University	2022
Modeling and Correcting Bias in Sequential Evaluation	
Rising Stars in Data Science Workshop, University of Chicago	2022
INFORMS Annual Meeting	2022
Information Theory and Applications Workshop (ITA)	2022
Debiasing Evaluations That Are Biased by Evaluations	
Women in EconCS, International Joint Conference on Theoretical Computer Science (IJTCS)	2021
Towards Understanding and Mitigating Biases	
Georgia Institute of Technology	2021
Harvard University	2021
Nanyang Technological University	2021
Peking University	2019

• The More You Look, the More You See: Towards General Object Understanding through Recursive Re National Robotics Engineering Center (NREC)	finement 2017
AWARDS	
Rising Stars in Data Science Workshop, University of Chicago	2022
Best Lightning Talk from College of Engineering, Fall 2022 Georgia Tech Postdoc Research Symposiu	m 2022
Best Research Talk from College of Engineering, Spring 2022 Georgia Tech Postdoc Research Symposi	um 2022
Ronald J. and Carol T. Beerman President's Postdoctoral Fellowship, Georgia Tech	2021
ARC (Algorithms & Randomness Center) Fellowship, Georgia Tech	2021
Best Paper Award Nomination, AAMAS 2019	
Best Student Paper Award, AAMAS 2019	
Travel scholarship, AAAI 2020, AAMAS 2019, WiML and HCML workshops at NeurIPS 2019	
Departmental Citation, UC Berkeley Recognition of outstanding undergraduate achievement within the department awarded to one graduating senior annually	2015
James H. Eaton Memorial Scholarship, UC Berkeley For a keen sense of creativity and inventiveness	2015
Kevin K. Gong Memorial Scholarship for Bright Minds and Big Hearts, UC Berkeley For passion about using technology to better the world	2015
Arthur M. Hopkin Award, UC Berkeley For seriousness of purpose and high academic achievement	2014
Berkeley Club of Hong Kong Undergraduate Scholarship, UC Berkeley	2014
Edward Frank Kraft Award for Freshmen, UC Berkeley	2012
SERVICE	
Reviewer: FAccT (2023), Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research (2022), Annals of Statistics (2021), AAAI (2021, 2022, 2023), STOC (2020), WiML NeurIPS (2019)	20), ISIT
Program committee member: HCOMP (2022), Learning with Strategic Agents workshop, AAMAS (20)22)
Qualifier committee member: Subhodeep Mitra (MS in Robotics, 2019)	
Undergraduate student mentoring: Komal Dhull, Carmel Baharav	
High school student mentoring: Charlotte Zhou (Bronx High School of Science, NY)	
Admissions committee member: Robotics Institute Summer Scholars (2019)	
Student volunteer: AAAI (2020), AAMAS (2019), ICML (2016)	
OUTREACH	
Speaker, Seminar on Diversity, Equity, Inclusion (DEI) and Bias, GT INFORMS Student Chapter	2022
Presenter, Mission Possible Summer Camp, Georgia Tech Led activities for high-school students in the summer camp to learn about industrial engineering research	2022
Grand award judge, Regeneron International Science and Engineering Fair (ISEF)	2022
Panelist, Tea with Summer Undergraduates, CMU	2019
Interview participant, the Girls Who Code Featured in the article https://womenincs.github.io/future.html	2019
Student volunteer, PhD student open house, CMU 20	19, 2021

• Understanding Biases in Assessment Problems
The Auton Lab, Carnegie Mellon University

Graduate student mentor, Robitics Institute Summer Scholars (RISS), CMU Mentored undergraduate students through the graduate school application process and provided sugge	2018 estions on the writing material
Outreach officer and webmaster, Society of Women Engineers (SWE) Organized middle and high school outreach events and designed the chapter's website	2011 – 2015
Member, Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society (HKN)	2013 – 2015
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Guest lecturer, PIC 16B (Python with Applications II), UCLA	Winter 2023
Guest lecturer, ISYE 6740 (Computational Data Analysis), Georgia Tech	Fall 2022
Teaching assistant, 16-720 (Computer Vision), CMU	Fall 2017
Lab assistant, EE 20N (Signals and Systems), UC Berkeley	Fall 2013
INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE	
Facebook Inc.	6.2014 - 8.2014
Software Engineering Intern, Privacy Infrastructure Team	
EMC Corporation	6.2013 - 8.2013
Software Engineering Intern, Advanced Storage Division	
PERSONAL INTERESTS	
Atlanta Community Symphony Orchestra Second Violin	2023 – present